Name: Beakal Lemeneh
Net ID: 31390484
Project Number: 04
Lab Section: Mon/Wed 4:50 pm-6:05 pm
I collaborated with Ermiyas Liyeh on this assignment.


Project 4

I worked on this project with Ermiyas Liyeh. We started working on this project on the weekends, so we didn't have the chance to demonstrate our work to our TAs. On this project, I worked with graphics and other frontend parts of the game, while Ermiyas worked on the projectile motion of the ball, integration of the ActionListener with the KeyListener, and the extra credits.

The game is played by a single player. The user must press the Enter key to start the game. The game progresses to different levels based on the performance of the player. What is required for a player to advance to the next level is explained on the comment part of the code. Once the player looses the game, the score of the player is displayed on the screen. If the score of the player is a high score, then it is stored as a high score and is displayed on the top of the screen. If a user wants to keep on playing the game, then the user can press the Enter key and keep on playing for as much as he/she desires.

We have extensively described how the game works on the comment part of the code by explaining most lines of the code. We have also worked on two extra credits.

One extra credit involves creating something cool worth doing, so me and Ermiyas came up with an idea to enable the user to play the game for as much as he/she wants even if he/she looses by pressing the Enter key. In other words, if a user looses the game, he/she can restart the game by pressing the Enter key. I hope this qualifies as something interesting.

The other extra credit is storing the high score of the game. Since a user can play the game repeatedly, then the high score is updated every time a user plays the game. The high score of the game is displayed on the top of the screen.





